Finding Aid for the The Donald Grady Davidson Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Research Notes
  - Research Notes (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Research Notes (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Research Notes (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Research Notes (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Corrections of unidentified book (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Chronicle of East Tennessee Settlements, pp. 2, 4-8 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Contemporary Southern Literature (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Dewey (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Notebook containing notes and sketches on several topics (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Leaders of Disassociation & Detachment (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Ronsard, Du Bellay, etc. (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Sketch of Libretto for Rip Van Winkle (one-act opera) (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Yeats (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Micsellaneous (Box 47, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous. Ballads (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous notes on the writings of others 19) Ft. Prince George (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - White Spirituals (Box 47, Folder 20)
  - Small black notebook containing notes on Wordsworth, Southey, Coleridge, Sir Walter Scott, Byron, Shelley, Keats, and others (Box 47, Folder 21)
- Subject Files
  - TVA (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - TVA (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - TVA (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - TVA (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - TVA (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - TVA (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - TVA (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - TVA Map of Tennessee (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - TVA Maps of Tennessee (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Tennessee Road Maps (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - The Tennessee Recreation Development of the Tennessee River System (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - The Tennessee-Prospective Commerce on the Tennessee River (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - "A Comparison of TVA: Miracle or Monster" by Tom Humphrey and The Tennessee, Vol. I and II by Donald Davidson" (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - "The TVA Plant Food Program" in The Nation's Agriculture (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Public Affairs Pamphlets, Public Service Magazine (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Nashville, Notes (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - George Pullen Jackson (Box 48, Folder 17)
    Obituary, Monday Jan. 19, 1953
    Tennessee Folklore Society Program, Nov. 7, 1953
    A New Catalog of Old Ballads, Folk Songs and Songsters from George Pullen Jackson.
    Spiritual Folk Songs of Early America, order form
  - Henry Miller. Newspaper Clippings and legal documents relating to Henry Miller and his book. (Box 48, Folder 18)
  - Hervey Allen Memorial. (Box 48, Folder 19)
- Subject Files
  - Bulletins and Newsletters (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Bulletins and Newsletters (Mark Twain Society brochure, Social Science Research Council offers for 1937-38, Post Mortem on the journal Secession, Amendment of Chapter 97 of the Code of Virginia, 1960) (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - State of Tennessee Financial Position, 1942 (Box 49, Folder 3)
- Book Announcements (Arranged by publisher (dealer) or by title if no publisher)
  - "A-H" (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - " I-O" (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - " R" (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - "S- T" and Miscellaneous (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Southern Policy Papers, #1-7, 9, 10, 1936 -1937, University of North Carolina (Box 49, Folder 8)
    #1 Southern Population and Social Planning by T. J. Woofter, Jr.
    #3 Social Legislation in the South by Charles W. Pipkin
    #4 How the Other Half is Housed-A Pictorial Record of Sub-Minimum Farm Housing in the South by Rupert B. Vance
    #5 Industrial Social Security in the South by Robin Hood
    #6 The Southern Press Considers the Constitution edited by Francis P. Miller
    #7 The TVA and Economic Security in the South by T. Levron Howard (2 copies)
    #9 Wage and Hour Legislation for the South by H. M. Douty
    #10 What is Regionalism by Harry E. Moore
  - Agriculture (Box 49, Folder 9)
    Small Grain in Contour Furrows on Lespedeza Sod, August 1939
    Soil: The Nation's Basic Heritage
    Test Demonstrator-Strength of Land for War and Peace, Dec. 1942
    The Volunteer Gardener, Official Publication of Tennessee Federation of Garden Clubs, 1962
    Test Demonstration Communities: Wartime Farming Activities in Organized Areas of Tennessee By Joe. A. Elliott
  - Agriculture (Box 49, Folder 10)
    Building a New Dominion, a Publication of the Southwest Virginia Agricultural Association, Jan. 1943
    Corrugated Farming: An Entirely New Method of Rain and Soil Control
    The Cotton and Cotton Oil Press, Proceedings of the Forty-Second Annual Convention, National Cottonseed Products Association, Inc., May 1938 11)
  - Jesse Stuart (Box 49, Folder 11)
    Jesse Stuart Newsletter
    Autobiographical Reminiscence
    Six Sonnets reprinted from the Colorado Quarterly, Autumn 1960
    Southern Observer, June 1959
    "My Father's Fifty Acres"
    Jesse Stuart Day, Oct. 15, 1955, Greenup, Kentucky
    Letter to Time magazine by Stuart
    Davidson's Letter of Recommendation for Stuart
  - Jesse Stuart (Box 49, Folder 12)
    " Faith and Jesse Stuart by Ralph Morrissey," The Nashville Tennessean, Jan. 30, 1955
    " Stuarts Arrive Back in America," Aug. 2, 1961
    Tennessean, Feb. 16, 1961
    "Stuart Receives American Poets Award," The Columbia Record, Dec. 13, 1961
  - Travel Folders (including Civil War Sites such as Fort Donelson National Military Park; Shiloh National Military Park; Fort Ticonderoga) (Box 49, Folder 13)
- Photographs of Writers (Complete list of these photographs found in Appendix D)
  - Aland - Austin (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Babbit - Bent (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Beveridge - Bogan (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Bojer - Brace (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Breadloaf - Bucovici (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Burke - Carver (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Catherine the Great - Conkling (Box 49, Folder 20)
  - Cornell - Delafield (Box 49, Folder 21)
  - Dewey - Duncan (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Eliot - Jake Falstaff (Box 49, Folder 23)
  - Charles Ferguson - Friedlaender (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - John Galsworthy - Green (Box 49, Folder 25)
  - Harriman-Herbert (Box 49, Folder 26)
  - Heyward - Huxley (Box 49, Folder 27)
  - Jackson - Josephson (Box 49, Folder 28)
  - Keats - de Kruif (Box 49, Folder 29)
  - Lardner - Lehman (Box 49, Folder 30)
  - Lewis - Mann (Box 49, Folder 31)
  - Marion - Maurois (Box 49, Folder 32)
  - Menken - More (Box 49, Folder 33)
  - Munson - North (Box 49, Folder 34)
  - Paine - Phelps (Box 49, Folder 35)
  - Pope - Robb (Box 49, Folder 36)
  - Roberts - Royde-Smith (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Russell - Schneider (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Scott - Sinclair (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Sir Ronald Storrs - Terhune (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Louis Untermeyer - Van Doren (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Henry Van Dyke - Walpole (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Wasserman - Walter White (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Thornton Wilder - Wodehouse (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Thomas Wolfe - Stark Young (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - The Taylor Bill, Correspondence, 1950-51 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - The Taylor Bill, Correspondence, 1950-51 (Box 50, Folder 11)
- Writings by Others
- Material Collected by Davidson-Publications
  - L'Alouette, Jan. - Feb. 1925 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - American Philosophical Society, Sept. 20, 1940 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - American Poetry Magazine, Sept. - Oct. 1924 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Annual Report of the Tennessee Valley Authority and Appendixes, June 30, 1934 (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Architectural Concrete (Box 50, Folder 13)
  - Arkansas State Policy Committee Published papers No. 1 and 2, October 31, 1936, April 1938 (Box 50, Folder 14)
  - Atlas the Magazine of the World Press (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - The Bard: Comrade of the Young Poet, Oct. 1923 (Box 50, Folder 15)
  - Blues, A Magazine of New Rhythms, March, April, May 1929 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Bozart, The Bi-Monthly Poetry Review, Jan. -Feb., 1929 (Box 50, Folder 16)
  - Broom, Sept. 1923, Oct. 1923 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - Buccaneer, A Journal of Poetry, Sept. 1924 (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Carpetbaggers of Industry by Thomas L. Stokes (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - Casements (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - The Circle, Sept. - Oct. 1924 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - IX. Charleston and Summerville, Jan. 1, 1927 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - The Classical Journal, Dec. 1946, April 1947 (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - Contemporary Verse, Nov. 1924 (Box 50, Folder 20)
  - The Criterion, April 1924 (Box 50, Folder 21)
  - Don Felipe: A Narrative Poem of Mexico by D. Maitland Bushby, copyright 1929 (Box 50, Folder 22)
  - The Double Dealer, July 1924, November - December 1924, May 1926 (published at New Orleans) (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Elements of Life, June 1940 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Engineering Geology, June 1934 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Engineering and Social Progress in the South, 1938 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Farming for Victory and Peace, 1942 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Food at the Grass Roots, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Forests and Human Welfare, 1940 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - The Forge, Nov. 1924 and September 1924 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Four A Quarterly, October 1924 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - The Gypsy: Cincinnati All Poetry Magazine, Spring 1925 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - How Cheap Electricity Pays Its Way, 1937 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Independence, Feb. 1931 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Interludes: A Magazine of Verse, 1924 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - The Interpreter, July 2 & 16, 1945 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - The Journal of Educational Sociology, November 1941 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - The Lariat, Nov. 1924 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Laughing Horse, September 1924 (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - The Little Review, Spring 1923, 1924 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - The Lyric, Dec. 1924 (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - The Measure, A Journal of Poetry, September 1924 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Memorandum of the Special Committee On Investment Public and Private, 1940 (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - The Midland, May 1924, June, July, August 1924 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - The Minaret, Nov.-Dec. 1924 (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Mississippi Population Trends and their Implications by Dr. J. V. Van Sickle, April 1943 (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - The New Republic, 1924; March 11, 1931 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - The Nomad, Spring 1924 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Orpheus, December 1924 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Palms, Early Fall 1924 (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Phantasmus, July - August 1924 (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Phosphate Resources of the United States, Jan. 1939 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - The Guild Pioneer, May 1923 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Poetry A Magazine of Verse, November 1924 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - The Reviewer, Jan. 1923, Jan. 1925 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Rural Youth by David Cushman Coyle, 1939 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - S4N Homage to Waldo Frank, 1923-1924 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Scientific Living, Dec. 1, 1929 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Secession, Winter 1924 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Seven Poems by Julian Rayford, May 6, 1931 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Sheila Kaye Smith: A Biographical Sketch, Some Critical Appreciations, and a Bibliography, 1929 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Tennessee Historical Quarterly, June 1943 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - The Testament of a Stone Being Notes on the Mechanics of the Poetic Image (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - The Transatlantic Review, Dec. 1924 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Tuttle's Literary Miscellany, Catalog 290 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - The Virginia Quarterly Review (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - The Writer and His Tradition, 1969 Southern Literary Festival, April 17-19, University of Tennessee, Robert Drake, editor and Cleanth Brooks, James Dickey, and Reynolds Price (Box 51, Folder 10)
- Material collected by Davidson-Articles by Others
  - "A - Coles" (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - "Coulter - D" (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - "E - Orwell" (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - "Parks - Shoup" (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - "Shryock - W"; Saturday Review of Literature; No authors (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Neuhoff, Karl. Amerikanische Kulturprobleme. (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings saved by Davidson-not about him, 1924-25 (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper Clippings saved by Davidson - not about him, 1926-29 (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings saved by Davidson - not about him, 1930-34 (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Newspaper Clippings saved by Davidson -not about him, March-May 16, 1936 (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - Newspaper Clippings saved by Davidson-not about him, May 19, 1936-1938 (Box 52, Folder 21)
  - Newspaper Clippings saved by Davidson-not about him, 1955-65 (Box 52, Folder 22)
- Book Reviews by Others
  - Edward Parks-A Man Born to Command by Emil Ludwig (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Elizabeth D. Wheatley-Mr. Weston's Good Wine by T. F. Powys (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Reviewer unknown-Hiawassee Island An Archaeological Account of Four Tennessee Indian Peoples by Thomas M. N.Lewis and Madeline Kneberg (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Reviewer unknown-Memoirs of the Life of William Wirt by J. P Kennedy (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Simon Jeune in Revue de Litterature Comparee (extrait) of Reality and Myth: Essays In American Literature in Memory of Richmond Croom Beatty edited by William E. Walker and Robert L. Welker, Vanderbilt University Press, 1964 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Reviewer unknown-Segments of Southern Thought by Edd W. Parks (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Reviewer unknown-The Tragic Era by Claude G. Bowers (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Edwin Mims-A Preface to Morals by Walter Lippman (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - John McClure-The Advancing South by Edwin Mims, June 20, 1926 (Box 53, Folder 3)
- Poems by Others (arranged by author)
  - Br - Mc (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Mi - Od (1) (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Od (2) - St (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Unger - Yancey, unknown authors (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Complete list of Poems by others (Fugitives & Agrarians located in that Series) (Box 53)
  - Cleanth Brooks- "Birth of Aphrodite" (Box 53)
  - Constantine Cavafy- "Thermopylae" (trans. by Raphael Demos) (Box 53)
  - Sam Clark (S. L. C.)-- "Research" (Box 53)
  - e.e. cummings-untitled (Box 53)
  - Hart Crane- "Lachrymae Christi" (with holograph note by Allen Tate) (Box 53)
  - Hart Crane- "Legend" (Box 53)
  - T.H. Davidson- "Prologue" (Box 53)
  - Emanuel Eisenberg- "Small Offering" (Box 53)
  - Marguerite Mather Eskind- "Hospitality" (Box 53)
  - Marguerite Mather Eskind- "Joy" (Box 53)
  - Edward McGehee- "No Storm for Fear" (Box 53)
  - "Parody on an Easy Poet" (Box 53)
  - "An Imaginative Child's Rainy Afternoon" (Box 53)
  - "The Seeburg Rocks Its Newest Love" (Box 53)
  - "There is a Season" (Box 53)
  - "An Unsung Requiem" (Box 53)
  - Margaret Beaufort Miller-- " Wanderer's Night Song" (Goethe) (Box 53)
  - "Hill Dreamer" (Box 53)
  - George Marion O'Donnell-"The Art of Pain" (Box 53)
  - "Autumn and Mrs. Noel, Old" (Box 53)
  - "Commencement Oration" (Box 53)
  - "Green Thought" (Box 53)
  - "In the Delta, Remembering" (Box 53)
  - "The Mask and the Poet " (Box 53)
  - "Mirrored Dead" (Box 53)
  - "Obituary" (Box 53)
  - "The Prophet Speaks" (Box 53)
  - "Prothalamion" (Box 53)
  - "Reprimand" (Box 53)
  - "Soliloquy upon Return" (Box 53)
  - "Song: To Exiled Art" (Box 53)
  - Isabel Tilden Riggs -"Shelley" (Box 53)
  - Jane Stuart-"The City of the Dead" (Box 53)
  - Leonard Unger-"Poem" (Box 53)
  - Grace Allen Yancey -"Cosmic Neglect" "Death Head" (Box 53)
  - "To Franz Hal's.. ." "Morning" (Box 53)
  - sent by Mrs. J. E. Blankenship- "A Song Called Hurrah for the Tennesseans" (Box 53)
  - "Southern Battle Song" (Box 53)
  - The Knot of Blue and Gray" (Box 53)
  - "The Homespun Dress" (Box 53)
  - Author unknown - "The Air" (Box 53)
- Manuscripts By Others
  - John P. Ferris-Business and the Tennessee Valley Watershed, Address before a meeting of the Johnson City, Tennessee Chamber of Commerce on, November 9, 1936 (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Herschel Gower-Untitled (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - John Temple Graves-Talk, Talk, and More Talk (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Verne P. Kaub-"What Is Really ‘Inside U.S.A,'" (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - John Hubert Overall-Criticism No. 1 (Box 53, Folder 10)
- Short Stories by Others
  - Jesse Stuart-"As a Man Thinketh." In Esquire (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Jesse Stuart-"Can You Win by Losing?" (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Author unknown-Untitled Description of a Writing Class (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Original Newspaper Clippings (Box 54)
  - Nashville Tennessean Book Review and Literary Page (Box 54)
  - Sept. 7, 1924 - April 29, 1928 The copies are in Writings-Editing Projects (Boxes 31-33) (Box 54)
  - Original Newspaper Clippings (Box 55)
  - Nashville Tennessean Book Review and Literary Page (Box 55)
  - May 6, 1928 - Oct. 26, 1930 (Box 55)
  - The photocopies of these newspaper clippings are in Writings-Editing Projects (Box 31-33) (Box 55)
  - Original Newspaper Clippings, 1926 -1965. Photocopies are in Boxes 35 and 36-Literary Career and in Box 52 --Writings by Others (Box 56)
  - Also in this box are photocopies of correspondence between Allen Tate and Davidson. (Box 56)
  - Correspondence envelopes (Box 57)
  - Photocopies of outgoing correspondence (Box 58)
  - May 17, 1917 - Nov. 1, 1939 (Box 58)
  - Photocopies of outgoing correspondence (Box 59)
  - March 11, 1940 - April 5, 1968 (Box 59)
  - The Fugitive (Box 60)
  - April 1922 - December 1925 (19 issues) (Box 60)
  - April 1922, June 1922 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - October 1922, December 1922 (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - February, March 1923 and April, May 1923 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - June, July 1923 and August, September 1923 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - October 1923 and December 1923 (Box 60, Folder 5)
  - February 1924 and April 1924 (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - June 1924 and August 1924 (Box 60, Folder 7)
  - December 1924 and March 1925 (Box 60, Folder 8)
  - June 1925 and September 1925 (Box 60, Folder 9)
  - December 1925 (Box 60, Folder 10)
  - These are various additions to the papers (Legal and Oversize): (Box 61)
  - Personal and Biographical Material-Resolution by the Board of Trust of Vanderbilt University in Memory of Donald Davidson, May 17, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Galley Proof (uncorrected proof) of American Composition and Rhetoric, Concise Edition (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Big Ballad Jamboree materials -correspondence and notes (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Big Ballad Jamboree- Chapters (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Conversation with Jack Dewitt, Station Manager, May 31, 1954, WSM Studio C Rehearsal ("Practice") for "Prince Albert" show, June 5, 1954; WSM Studio C (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Singin'Billy Materials (Box 62)
  - - -Orchestra parts for Singin' Billy- music for the various instruments (Box 62)
  - - -Singin' Billy an Opera in Two Acts, Music by Charles Faulkner Bryan and Drama and Lyrics by Donald Davidson with Spirituals adapted from William Walker's Southern Harmony, copyright 1952. (Box 62)
  - - -Singin' Billy Overture (copyrighted 1952) (Box 62)
  - - -Singin' Billy Orchestral Score Act I, Sc. Ii, Act II, sc.i (Box 62)
  - - -Singin' Billy Orchestral Score Act II, sc, ii (Box 62)
  - Singin' Billy Materials (Box 63)
  - - - Singin' Billy- Correspondence, 1952 - 1955 (Box 63)
  - - -Singin' Billy - Libretto and Correspondence with Charles F. Bryan (Box 63)
  - - -Donald Davidson's personal copy of Singin' Billy an Opera in Two Acts, Copyright, 1952 by Donald Davidson and Charles Faulkner Bryan (Box 63)
  - - -Singin' Billy an Opera by Donald Davidson and Charles F. Bryan, Copy No. B-3 (Box 63)
  - - -Singin' Billy an Opera in Two Acts, music by Charles Faulkner Bryan, Drama and Lyrics by Donald Davidson, copyright 1952. Copy no. 121 (Box 63)
  - - -Singin' Billy an Opera in Two Acts, music by Charles Faulkner Bryan, Drama and Lyrics by Donald Davidson, copyright 1952 (Box 63)
  - - -Recordings of Singin' Billy: (Box 63)
    No. 1, No. 3
    No. 2, No. 4
    No. 5, No. 7
    No. 6, No. 8
    No. 10, No. 12
    No. 9, No. 11
    No., 13, No. 14
  - - -Other Recordings: (Box 63)
    Lee in the Mountains and Sanctuary read by Earl Foster student in the College of the Ozarks, Clarksville, Arkansas
  - - -Audio Cassette Tapes (Box 63)
    Singin' Billy (3 tapes)
    Singin' Billy (4 tapes)
  - Singin' Billy An Opera in Two Acts (typescript of 137 pages) (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Singin' Billy An Opera in Two Acts, Music by Charles Faulkner Bryan, Drama and Lyrics by Donald Davidson (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - 2 typescripts of The Big Ballad Jamboree A Novel by Donald Davidson (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous photographs and newspaper clippings collected by Davidson including Americana, the South and the Confederacy items, and Writers (with pipes) (Box 65)
  - Photographs--Americana (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Photographs-The South and the Confederacy (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Photographs-Writers (with pipes) (October 1955) (Box 64, Folder 3)
- DONALD DAVIDSON PAPERS
- APPENDIX A -- LIST OF POEMS WRITTEN BY DAVIDSON
- WRITINGS-POEMS
  - Admonition to the Dead
  - Advice to Shepherds
  - Aftermath
  - All Fool's Calendar
  - II Calendar
  - All Fool's Calendar
  - All Fool's Calendar
  - Androcles Again
  - Assembly
  - Assembly at Murfreesboro
  - At the Torture Post
  - Aunt Maria and the Gourds
  - Avalon
  - A Barren Look
  - Battle Vow
  - Bird of Paradise
  - Blood of Heroes
  - Boudoir
  - Boundary
  - Bryony
  - Burial of an Idea
  - Cabined
  - The Case of Motorman 17: Commitment Proceedings
  - The Charm
  - Charm Against the Evil Eye
  - Charm for the Evil Eye
  - The Charmless One
  - Cities of Refuge
  - Coat of Arms
  - Color Blind
  - Competition
  - Corymba
  - Country Music
  - Countersong
  - Country Roses: A Song
  - Crabbed Youth and Age
  - Crabbed Youth and Merry Age/ Southward Returning
  - Crabbed Youth and Merry Age
  - Crime
  - Cross Question, Crooked Answer: A Civil War Seminar
  - Cumberland Bound
  - Bound for Cumberland
  - Curve
  - David Crockett
  - The Deserter: A Christmas Eclogue
  - Desolate Stream
  - A Dirge
  - Dryan-from An Outland Piper
  - Earthbound
  - Ecclesiasticus
  - Echo
  - An Epinician Ode in Honor of John Crowe Ransom
  - The Family Trouble-Motorman 17: Commitment Proceedings
  - A Farewell
  - Fear in a Cubicle
  - Fiddler Dow
  - First Alienist, part of Case of Motorman 17
  - For a Student Celebration
  - For Example
  - Forrest Rides
  - Four Sacred
  - From a Window
  - Funeral in a Garden
  - The Game
  - A God at Bay
  - Gradual of the Northern Summer
  - Graph of the Cosmos
  - Graph of the Cosmos
  - Gravure
  - Guest at Morning
  - Handicap
  - Harold Pennybunch
  - Hermitage
  - Hermitage
  - Hit or Miss
  - The House of No Surrender
  - Hunter
  - Idyl
  - In Blue Stocking Hollow: Bedford County
  - Jasper
  - Joe Clisby's Song
  - John Darrow
  - Johnnie Armstrong
  - The Last Charge
  - The Last Rider
  - The Last Rider
  - Lee in the Mountains, 1865 -1870
  - Legend
  - Lines Written for Allen Tate
  - Lines for a Tomb
  - Lines to Atticus
  - Litany
  - Long Green
  - Manslaughter
  - Martha and Shadow
  - Meeting with Scylla
  - Morning Love
  - Morning was Golden
  - Naiad in The Double Dealer
  - The Nervous Man
  - Ninth Part of Speech
  - Ninth Part of Speech
  - Not Long Green
  - Ode to the Home Town
  - Old Black Joe Comes Home
  - The Old Man of Thorn
  - On Culleoka Road
  - On a Replica of the Parthenon
  - On Winstead Hill
  - Palingenesis
  - Pastoral -In the Modern Style
  - Pavane
  - Peek-a-Boo!
  - Plus and Minus
  - Portraits of Three Ladies
  - A Prayer
  - Preface
  - Priapus Younger
  - Projection of a Body Upon Space
  - Randall, My Son
  - The Rebel Yell
  - Resume
  - Retreat
  - Return in Autumn
  - Ritual of a Summer Day
  - Riddle of a Day Summer
  - Robertson County Nights
  - The Running of Streight
  - The Running of Streight
  - The Running of Streight
  - The Running of Streight
  - Second Harvest
  - Sequel of Appomattox
  - Sideways Forever
  - Sky Mark
  - Soldier and Son
  - Southward Returning
  - Spoken at a Castle Gate
  - Stone and Roses
  - A Study in Shadows
  - The Swan
  - Swan and Exile
  - The Swinging Bridge
  - The Terrible
  - To-
  - To Anybody
  - To the Army of Tennessee
  - To the Army of Tennessee
  - To Tom, A Yowling
  - To An Unwilling Student
  - To See Through All Things
  - A Toast: From Bread Loaf to Elizabeth Drews